{"tossups": [{"question": "Journalist George Plimpton helped wrestle a man to the floor during this event. A widely-published photograph taken in the aftermath of this event shows busboy Juan Romero crouching on a concrete floor. The perpetrator of this event, who claimed to have been motivated by its target\u2019s pro-Israeli views, fired a 22 caliber handgun into a crowd at the Ambassador Hotel in Los Angeles, targeting and killing a Presidential candidate. For the point, name this 1968 event committed by Sirhan Sirhan.", "answer": "<b> assassination</b> (or<b> murder</b>,<b> shooting</b>, etc.) of<b> R</b>obert<b> Kennedy</b> (accept<b> assassination</b> of <b>RFK</b>; prompt on partial answers, such as \u201cassassination of Kennedy\u201d) (2) This city\u2019s namesake affair was a series of purges orchestrated by Malenkov and Beria. Operation Iskra and the Sinyavino Offensive attempted to relieve this city, which was supplied by the Road of Life. The siege of this city was lifted by a corridor over neighboring Lake Ladoga, and was the target of Army Group North during Operation Barbarossa. For the point, name this city, a former capital of Russia that was besieged by Nazi Germany for over two years. ANSWER:<b> Leningrad</b> (accept<b> St. Petersburg</b>; accept<b> Petrograd</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "William Duane briefly served as Secretary of the Treasury under this president, during whose term\u201cHard Times tokens\u201d began to be minted as private currency. This president and his Secretary of the Treasury, Levi Woodbury, called for land purchases to be made in gold and silver in the Specie Circular. This President\u2019s refusal to renew the charter of the Second Bank of the United States led to the Bank War. For the point, name this president who passed a precarious economic situation to his successor, Martin van Buren.", "answer": "Andrew<b> Jackson</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "A battle at this location was won when William Miller refused to turn over a vital key, buying Joseph Stilwell\u2019s Marines time to secure this location. Miran Thompson and Sam Shockley were executed for instigating an uprising in this location. Frank Morris and the Anglin brothers drowned after attempting to leave this place by raft. Al Capone served out his sentence at, for the point, what prison, believed to have been escape proof, that was located on an island in San Francisco Bay?", "answer": "<b> Alcatraz</b> (accept additional information relating to the island and/or the prison; prompt on San Francisco Bay before mentioned) Page 1", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This author described \u201cSixteen million sleepers and pickets in the dark: / Some of them long sleepers for always\u201d in his poem \u201cKillers.\u201d This writer declared \u201cI cover all\u201d in a poem that opens with the command \u201cPile the bodies high at Austerlitz and Waterloo.\u201d This author of \u201cGrass\u201d wrote a two-part biography of Abraham Lincoln subtitled<em> The Prairie Years</em> and<em> The War Years</em>. For the point, name this poet who used the phrase \u201cHog Butcher for the World\u201d to describe his home city of \u201cChicago.\u201d", "answer": "Carl<b> Sandburg</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Poetry"}, {"question": "Governor Robert Pattison called in the state militia to enforce martial law during this event, which broke the power of the Amalgamated Association union. During this event, leftover fireworks from recent Independence Day celebrations were fired on two ships containing Pinkerton agents on the Ohio River. While this event was ending, Alexander Berkman tried but failed to assassinate Henry Clay Frick. For the point, name this 1892 strike of steel workers in a Pennsylvania mill owned by Andrew Carnegie.", "answer": "<b> Homestead</b> Strike", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "On this body of water, Joshua Barney led a flotilla of gunboats during the War of 1812. Dredgers in this body of water invented the motorless skipjack boat to optimize their catch. This body of water was the site of Thomas Graves\u2019 loss to the Admiral de Grasse, thwarting British attempts to resupply troops at Yorktown. A vital population of blue crabs lives in this bay, which is fed by the Susquehanna and Potomac Rivers. For the point, name this large bay that borders Delaware, Maryland, and Virginia.", "answer": "<b> Chesapeake</b> Bay", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "For the point, name this country where dictator Nicolae Ceausescu ruled from Bucharest.", "answer": "<b> Romania</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "During World War II, this region was targeted by Operation Bustard Hunt, where one side struck the Kerch Peninsula in an attempt to break a siege. In an earlier conflict, the 93rd Highlanders became honored as the Thin Red Line in this region, where Lord Raglan made his name launching a courageous assault upon a Russian battery during the siege of Sevastopol. The Charge of the Light Brigade took place on, for the point, what Russian peninsula in the Black Sea, the subject of an 1850s war?", "answer": "<b> Crimea</b>n Peninsula (accept<b> Kerch</b> Peninsula before mentioned; prompt on Russia before mentioned; prompt on the Black Sea before mentioned", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This country\u2019s politics featured the left-wing Barisan Socialis until their supporters were rounded up in Operation Coldstore, paving the way for the People\u2019s Action Party to assert dominance. This country holds the distinction of being the only one to unwillingly gain its independence; its first prime minister, Lee Kuan Yew, cried on television after this country was expelled from Malaysia. For the point, name this city-state on the southern tip of the Malay Peninsula.", "answer": "Republic of<b> Singapore</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "The appointment of this man to a government position was reportedly called \u201cthe biggest damned-fool mistake I ever made\u201d by the appointing president. This man, who got his start as the district attorney of Alameda County, was the losing vice presidential candidate in 1948. This three-time governor of California chaired the commission that investigated the assassination of John F. Kennedy. For the point, name this politician who served as Chief Justice of the Supreme Court during the 1950s and 60s.", "answer": "Earl<b> Warren</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "One speech by this man asks whether his party will fight on the side of \u201cidle holders of idle capital\u201dor on the side of \u201cthe struggling masses.\u201d As Secretary of State, this politician signed many \u201cTreaties for the Advancement of Peace\u201d and resigned after witnessing the outcry over the<em> Lusitania</em>\u2019s sinking. This bimetallist declared that \u201cyou shall not crucify mankind\u201d in an 1896 speech. For the point, name this populist politician and orator of the \u201cCross of Gold\u201d speech.", "answer": "William Jennings<b> Bryan</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "RAF commander Richard Pink led strafing raids in this modern-day country, where the Faqir of Ipi led insurgents against the British. This modern country\u2019s former Northwest Frontier province was bounded by the Durand Line, and it includes a large Pashtun population in Waziristan. Shortly after Muhammad Ali Jinnah became governor general of this nation, conflict broke out with its majority Hindu neighbor. The Jammu and Kashmir state is disputed by China, India, and, for the point, what nation governed from Islamabad?", "answer": "Islamic Republic of<b> Pakistan</b> Page 4", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "Machin\u2019s formula for approximating this value was beaten by a formula based on modular equations discovered by Ramanujan. The 5th century Chinese astronomer Zu Chongzhi discovered approximations named \u201cMilu\u201d for this number, one of which was 355 over 113. Archimedes used a polynomial algorithm to obtain lower and upper bounds for the value of this constant. For the point, name this constant, equal to the ratio of a circle\u2019s circumference to its diameter, which is roughly equal to 3.14.", "answer": "<b> pi</b>", "metadata": "Science - Other Science - Math"}, {"question": "This man destroyed the Irminsul artifact and committed the massacre of Verden in his attempts to destroy pagan tribes. In another expedition, this man defeated Desiderius and conquered the Lombard kingdom, though he was less successful when Basque troops destroyed his rearguard in Roncevaux Pass in the Pyrenees. This son of Pepin the Short was coronated on Christmas Day by Pope Leo III. For the point, name this Frankish king who was crowned Holy Roman Emperor in 800.", "answer": "<b> Charlemagne</b> (or<b> Charles the Great</b>; accept<b> Charles I</b>; accept<b> Carolus Magnus</b>; accept <b>Karl de Grosse</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "One of these buildings in Brunswick Town, North Carolina, was burned by the British during the Revolutionary War. Richard Allen converted a blacksmith shop into one of these buildings in the 1790s in Philadelphia. Jonathan Edwards worked at one of these buildings in Northampton. Two lanterns were hung in one of these buildings in Boston as part of Paul Revere\u2019s Ride. Boston\u2019s Old North and Trinity are, for the point, what type of building for Christian congregations?", "answer": "<b> church</b>es Page 5", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This man was given a nickname translating as \u201ctown destroyer\u201d by Native Americans after he won the Battle of Jumonville Glen, though he shortly afterwards surrendered his contingent of troops at Fort Necessity. This man, who was Edward Braddock\u2019s chief aide during the French and Indian War, attacked a group of unprepared Hessian soldiers on the day after Christmas. For the point, name this commander of the Continental Army who won the Battle of Trenton after crossing the Delaware River in 1776.", "answer": "George<b> Washington</b> <b>Extra Question</b> Only read if moderator botches a question.", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The native name for this empire describes the union of four provinces, or<em> suyu</em>. One ruler of this empire led the successful conquest of another empire centered at Chan Chan known for its monochromatic pottery style, the Chim\u00b4u. Manco Yupanqui [yu-pahn-kee] founded a breakaway state of this empire in Vilcabamba five years after a civil war in this empire ended in the defeat of a half-brother of Huasc\u00b4ar, Atahualpa. The siege of Cuzco was fought by, for the point, what Peruvian empire that was conquered by the Spanish under Francisco Pizarro?", "answer": "<b> Inca</b>n Empire Page 6", "metadata": "History - World History"}], "bonuses": []}